Kruthik Gandhi HA

SUMMARY

I am a conscientious software developer with strong analytical abilities who has experience building and designing software in a test-driven environment, I have the aptitude to create user-centric end-user applications because I have a passion for finding solutions to issues and offering practical ones

CONTACT

Phone: +91-7090923709

Email: kruthikgandhi1119@gmail.com Location: Bengaluru, Karnataka

LINKS

Portfolio:

kruthik9880.github.io/portfolio/ Github:

github.com/kruthik9880

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/kruthik-gandhi-h-a-82a61a1b0/

COURSES

UNDERGRADUATE

Developing Android Apps with Kotlin by Google on **Udacity** AWS Cloud Technical Essentials on **Coursera**

Google IT Support on **Coursera**Python for Everybody Specialization on **Coursera**

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

• C++ • HTML • Kotlin • Python • Java

FRAMEWORKS

• CSS • PHP

TECHNOLOGIES

- Cloud Computing UI/UX Design
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Web Development

DATABASES

• MySQL • Oracle DB

IDE

• Android Studio • Intelli J

EDUCATION

VISVESVARAYA TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY | INFORMATION

SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug 2018 - July 2022 | Bangalore

TRISHANA TECHNOLOGIES ADVANCED PYTHON FOR WEB

DEVELOPMENT

March 2021 - June 2021 | Bengaluru

EXPERIENCE

GAOTEK | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sep 2021 – Dec 2021 | Bangalore

Designed and implemented the backend for various event management solutions

Analyzed and improved the navigation pane on the company's website

Developed web pages for latest products like 'GAOTek 10/100/1000M Gigabit PoE Injector' and 'GAOTek 12 Core Fiber Optic Splice Tray'

Collaborated and developed the setup page for 'BeaconSET', an android application to scan, connect, read and modify BeaconPlus devices via BLE (Bluetooth Low Energy)

EAST POINT COLLEGE | STUDENT PLACEMENT COORDINATOR

Mar 2019 - June 2021 | Bangalore

Kept track of and updated the status of all students and their placement process Handled all requirements in placement timeline

AWARDS

2022 1st/54 East Point Inter Department Academic Project Competition

2022 State Karnataka State Council for Science and Technology Finalist (KSCST)

PROJECTS

AUTOMATED BUS MANAGEMENT SYSTEM | KSCST

Nov 2021 - Jan 2022

An IOT project aimed at improving the bus travelling experience. It uses RFID tags for traveller count and it is used to collect fare

It also comes with an android application(telegram bot) which is specific to the user and can generate journey details and fare

It can also report accidents with the location of the bus, to the nearest hospital Stack: Embedded C. Arduino. EM-18

CLI DATA VAULT July 2021 - Aug 2021

A simple, stand-alone python command line interface application which encrypts and stores files and images in a secure vault(database)

Stack: Python, SQLite

WEATHER APP Feb 2021 - Mar 2021

Weather App built on Java using Open Weather's 'Current Weather Data API' to get current weather data of any city in the world

Stack: Java, Android Studio

MUSIC LIBRARY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM Dec 2020 - Jan 2021

The objective of this project is to store music based on respective genre, for exampleedm, indie, pop, rap, etc It aids in selection of genre - specific music at the external level, music is stored in the file-system as per their respective categories Stack: Java, Android Studio